The Dolphin Hotel invites you to stay in any of its stunning rooms. Except one.
1408 is a horror, mystery film directed by Mikael Håfström.
A man who specializes in debunking paranormal occurrences checks
into the fabled room 1408 in the Dolphin Hotel.
Soon after settling in, he confronts genuine terror.
Mike Enslin, played by John Cusack.
Gerald Olin, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Lilly Enslin, played by Mary McCormack.
Katie, played by Jasmine Jessica Anthony.
Sam Farrell, played by Tony Shalhoub.
Young Woman at Bookstore, played by Alexandra Silber.
1408 is a 2007 American psychological horror film based on
Stephen King's short story published in 1999.
It was directed by Mikael Håfström, written by Matt Greenberg, Scott
Alexander and Larry Karaszewski, and stars John Cusack and Samuel L.
The film follows Mike Enslin, an author who
investigates allegedly haunted places.
Enslin receives an ominous warning not to enter room 1408
at a New York City hotel, The Dolphin.
Although skeptical of the paranormal, he is soon trapped in the room,
where he experiences bizarre and frightful events.
1408 was released in the United States on June 22, 2007, by
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (under The Weinstein Company).
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was a box-office
success, grossing $133 million against a production budget of $25 million.
The film explores themes of hotel, hotel room, new york city, research, fire.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.